<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Publishing DTD v1.0 20120330//EN" "http://jats.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/1.0/JATS-journalpublishing1.dtd">
<article article-type="research-article" xml:lang="en"
	xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
	<?origin annotum?>
	<front>
		<journal-meta>
			<journal-id journal-id-type="publisher"/>
			<journal-title-group>
				<journal-title>Journal of Open Psychology Data</journal-title>
			</journal-title-group>
			<issn>2050-9863</issn>
			<publisher>
				<publisher-name>Ubiquity Press</publisher-name>
			</publisher>
		</journal-meta>
		<article-meta>
			<article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5334/jopd.ab</article-id>
			<article-categories>
				<subj-group>
					<subject>Data paper</subject>
				</subj-group>
			</article-categories>
			<title-group>
				<article-title>Data from “Changes in test-taking patterns over time” concerning the
					Flynn Effect in Estonia</article-title>
			</title-group>
			<contrib-group>
				<contrib>
					<name>
						<surname>Must</surname>
						<given-names>Olev</given-names>
					</name>
					<email/>
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff-1"/>
				</contrib>
				<contrib>
					<name>
						<surname>Must</surname>
						<given-names>Aasa</given-names>
					</name>
					<email/>
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff-2"/>
				</contrib>
			</contrib-group>

			<aff id="aff-1">Department of Psychology, University of Tartu, Tartu, Estonia</aff>
			<aff id="aff-2">Estonian National Defence College, Tartu, Estonia</aff>

			<pub-date publication-format="electronic" iso-8601-date="2014-03-18">
				<day>18</day>
				<month>03</month>
				<year>2014</year>
			</pub-date>

			<volume>2</volume>
			<issue>1</issue>
			<elocation-id>e2</elocation-id>
			<permissions>
				<copyright-statement>Copyright: &#x00A9; 2014 The Author(s)</copyright-statement>
				<copyright-year>2014</copyright-year>
				<license license-type="open-access"
					xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
					<license-p>This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the
						Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License (CC-BY 3.0), which permits
						unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the
						original author and source are credited. See
						http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/.</license-p>
				</license>
			</permissions>
			<self-uri xlink:href="http://openpsychologydata.metajnl.com/article/view/jopd.ab/"/>
			<abstract>
				<p>The dataset from our previous <italic>Intelligence</italic> paper [<xref
						ref-type="bibr" rid="B1">1</xref>] consists of data collected from the
					National Intelligence Tests (NIT, Estonian adaptation) at two historical time
					points: in 1933/36 (N=890) and in 2006, (N=913). The average age of the students
					was 13 years. The data-file consists of information about the cohort, age, and
					gender and test results at the item level for nine of the ten NIT subtests and
					subtest scores for the 10<sup>th</sup> subtest. The three answer types are
					separated into three categories: right answers, wrong answers and missing
					answers. Data can be used for the psychometric research of cohort and sex
					differences at the scale and item level.</p>
			</abstract>
			<kwd-group kwd-group-type="simple">
				<kwd>Flynn Effect</kwd>
				<kwd>National Intelligence Tests</kwd>
				<kwd>Tork</kwd>
				<kwd>test taking pattern</kwd>
				<kwd>Estonia</kwd>
			</kwd-group>
			<funding-group>
				<funding-statement>Estonian Scientific Foundation: grant no 2387 and 5856. European
					Social Fund: a Primus grant (#3-8.2/60) to Anu Realo. Baylor University
					financial support for data quality control in the archive. </funding-statement>
			</funding-group>

		</article-meta>
	</front>
	<body>
		<sec>
			<title>(1) Overview</title>
			<sec>
				<title>Context</title>
				<p>The study concerns the Flynn Effect (FE), or the secular increase in intelligence
					(IQ) test scores over time. Two cohorts of the same age are compared based on
					the results of the same 10 subtests of mental abilities. Must and Must [<xref
						ref-type="bibr" rid="B1">1</xref>] provide a detailed account of the study
					and the data collection from the 1930s and from 2006.</p>
				<p>Two unique historical circumstances made this study possible. In the early 1930s
					Estonian educators sought instruments which would allow them to measure a
					student’s intelligence to be able to influence their educational careers for the
					better. It was decided to adapt the National Intelligence Tests into Estonian –
					tests that were originally developed to measure students’ IQ in United States
						[<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">2</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B3"
						>3</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr"
						rid="B5">5</xref>]. This work was headed by Juhan Tork. He took this duty
					quite seriously as the analysis of the test adaptation process and the
					elaboration of IQ norms of Estonian students were the main focus of his PhD
					dissertation: “The Intelligence of Estonian Children” in 1939 [<xref
						ref-type="bibr" rid="B6">6</xref>].</p>
				<p>Although The Second World War and Soviet occupation set back Estonian society and
					intellectual life for half of a century, most of the completed test materials
					were kept in the repository of the Estonian National Historical Archive.
					Although most of the data was collected from southern Estonia, Tork’s
					interpretation was that the results of his work were representative for entire
					Estonia. The availability of real historical test- data made the Flynn Effect
					comparisons possible decades later. The second measurement, undertaken with the
					aim to estimate the FE in Estonia was done in 2006.</p>
			</sec>
			<sec>
				<title>Collection date(s)</title>
				<p>Estimation of the FE means comparisons of test results of comparable cohorts from
					different time periods. The first testing was done in 1933 - 1936 and the second
					in 2006.</p>
			</sec>
			<sec>
				<title>Background</title>
				<p>The scientific roots of this project are related to the history of IQ
					measurement. The development and application of IQ tests in the army recruiting
					process during The First World War was successful and led up to a major
					expansion of the use of IQ tests beyond the army. The American army tests (Army
					Alfa and Army Beta) served as the basis for the development of the next
					generations of testing instruments and approaches. The test, titled
						<italic>National Intelligence Tests</italic> (NIT) sought to measure the
					intelligence of schoolchildren (grades 3 to 8) and was developed by a team of
					psychologists – M. Haggerty, L. Terman, E. Thorndike, G. Whipple and R. Yerkes
					– who had previous experience with American Army Mental Tests [<xref
						ref-type="bibr" rid="B7">7</xref>]. The NIT was adapted into Estonian at the
					beginning of the 1930s. The test name in Estonian is “Intelligentsustestid”
					(Intelligence tests).</p>
			</sec>
		</sec>

		<sec>
			<title>(2) Methods</title>
			<p>The NIT is a timed test administered in paper-and-pencil format. It consists of two
				complementary scales (A and B) in two parallel forms (I and II). Both scales – A and
				B - consist of 5 subtests.</p>
			<p><list list-type="bullet">
					<list-item>
						<p>Arithmetical Reasoning (A1). The subtest consists of 16 items that
							require the test taker to find a solution to an unknown quantity. For
							example: “How many seats are there in 7 rooms, if each room has 30
							seats?”</p>
					</list-item>
					<list-item>
						<p>Sentence Completion (A2). The subtest consists of 20 items that require
							the test taker to fill in a missing word to make sentence understandable
							and correct. An example: “The letter …… came …… good news”.</p>
					</list-item>
					<list-item>
						<p>Concepts (A3). The subtest consists of 24 items requiring the selection
							of two characteristic features from among those given. For example,
							“apple: basket/redness/seeds/skin/sweetness”.</p>
					</list-item>
					<list-item>
						<p>Same–Different (A4). The subtest consists of 40 items requiring the
							evaluation of whether the meaning of the words presented is the same or
							different. For example, “brief….short; elevate…raise”.</p>
					</list-item>
					<list-item>
						<p>Symbol–Digit (A5). The subtest consists of 120 items requiring a decision
							as to which digit should be assigned a symbol based on a key; 9
							different symbols were presented. An abridged example of the key: ∞ □ Δ
							1 2 3 </p>
					</list-item>
					<list-item>
						<p>Computation (B1). The subtest consists of 22 items requiring addition,
							subtraction, multiplication, and division of both integers and
							fractions. For example, subtract: 38260 − 17700.</p>
					</list-item>
					<list-item>
						<p>Information (B2). The subtest consists of 40 items of everyday knowledge.
							For example, “The day before Thursday is:
							Wednesday/Tuesday/Friday/Monday”.</p>
					</list-item>
					<list-item>
						<p>Vocabulary (B3). The test consists of 40 items requiring knowledge of the
							qualities of different objects (<italic>yes</italic> and
								<italic>no</italic> answers), for example, “Does a dog have five
							legs?”</p>
					</list-item>
					<list-item>
						<p>Analogies (B4). The test consists of 32 items requiring the transference
							of the relation of two given words to other presented words. For
							example, baby – cries; cat - : mews/hole/little/dog. </p>
					</list-item>
					<list-item>
						<p>Comparisons (B5). The test consists of 50 items requiring judgment of the
							sameness of sets of numbers, family names, and graphic symbols presented
							in two columns. For example, Lindpere A. J. … Lindpere J. A.</p>
					</list-item>
				</list></p>
			<p>Both the original NIT-tests in English and the Estonian adaptation are subject to
				copyright and are available from the authors upon request.</p>
			<sec>
				<title>Samples</title>
				<p>The data for the sample from 1933/36 was taken from the Estonian National
					Historical Archive (foundation EAA.2101). There is data from approximately 5000
					persons in the archive depository. However various persons have completed
					different combinations of test forms and scales (for example, scale A form I and
					scale B form II etc.).</p>
				<p>The main inclusion criterion in the sample formation for the current study was
					that all students in this sample have filled out both forms of the second
					version of the test. Our preliminary pilot study revealed that the second
					version of the scales (A II and B II) is more appropriate for re-use decades
					later (due to the content of vocabulary and information subtest). Hence we
					sought only those specific cases from the archive that met this inclusion
					criterion.</p>
				<p>The second inclusion criterion was the school grade. In the 1930s, the compulsory
					basic school had 6 grades. The intellectual level of graduates of this
					educational level was of great interest to J.Tork. At the same time he tested
					students from other grades also, mainly those preceding the 6<sup>th</sup>
					grade. The largest portion of historical data derives from students of the
						4<sup>th</sup> to 6<sup>th</sup> grades. The typical age of this group is 12
					to 14 years. Those parameters guided the selection of a younger cohort in our
					study. In 2006 this group corresponded mostly with students from the
						6<sup>th</sup> to 8<sup>th</sup> grades. The formation of the sample of the
					younger cohort was guided by the aim of being as comparable as possible to the
					older one. This means that we were seeking schools and students from the same
					region (mainly from southern Estonia), and from the grades 6 to 8, where the
					typical student is 12 to 14 years old.</p>
				<p>The older cohort (1933/36; N = 890) consisted of students from grades 4 to 6,
					with a mean age of 13.3 (SD = 1.24) years whereas the younger cohort (2006, N =
					913) were from the grades 6 to 8 with a mean age of 13.5 (SD = .93) years.</p>
				<p>The samples are different at least in two important points: <list
						list-type="bullet">
						<list-item>
							<p>Educational differences. The younger cohort has had two more years of
								education than the older one. This difference is related to the
								lowering of the age of obligatory school attendance in Estonia. The
								educational difference may have a significant impact on the test
								results. For Tork himself schooling differences were also important.
								He found that the students’ age and grade were intertwined with the
								test results. Tork [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B6">6</xref>, p 192-
								205] devoted a whole chapter to this co-variation and calculated
								age-grade IQ norms. The same-aged students in the higher grades
								averaged higher test scores.</p>
						</list-item>
						<list-item>
							<p>Urbanization differences. Tork [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B6"
									>6</xref>, p 212-218] noticed that the rural-urban dimension
								creates significant differences in test results. He found that this
								difference is equal to one year of schooling. He believed that there
								should be different IQ norms for urban and rural students. Changes
								over the decades in the urbanization rate of the population may have
								influenced the estimation of the FE in Estonia.</p>
						</list-item>
					</list>
				</p>
				<p>In both cohorts the tests were administered in groups, based on school-grade, in
					a regular classroom, during a regular school day. Students who were absent from
					school on the testing day were not tested. There were only a few absentees in
					each group. We interpreted this as a random event. The participation rate was
					not fixed. </p>
			</sec>
			<sec>
				<title>Procedures</title>
				<p>The testing procedures of the NIT resembled testing in a military context. From
					test-takers, full obedience to the procedures was required. “Directions, and
					especially commands, should be spoken authoritatively, and instant obedience
					should be expected and required. Every child should obey promptly and without
					question.” [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B3">3</xref>, p.6; 6, p.69]. Exercise
					examples of items preceded each subtest. The procedure established exact timing
					requirements which were set for both pre-subtests and real tests (Table <xref
						ref-type="table" rid="T1">1</xref>). The NIT procedure included 20 different
					timing episodes. Commands such as “Ready — Go!”, “Stop!”, “Pencil up!” are
					typical commands in the NIT testing manual. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B6"
						>6</xref>, p 69 – 75]).</p>
				<table-wrap id="T1">
					<label>Table 1</label>
					<caption>
						<p>Time limits and the NIT scoring system.</p>
					</caption>
					<table>
						<tr>
							<th align="left" colspan="1" valign="bottom"/>
							<th align="left" colspan="2">Pre-test</th>
							<th align="left" colspan="4" valign="bottom">Test</th>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td align="center" colspan="7">
								<hr/>
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<th align="center"/>
							<th align="center">No of items in pre-test</th>
							<th align="center">Minutes per pre-test</th>
							<th align="center">No of items in subtest</th>
							<th align="center">Minutes per subtest</th>
							<th align="center">Sec per item</th>
							<th align="left">Scoring algorithm</th>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td colspan="7">
								<hr/>
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td align="left">Arithmetical Reasoning (A1)</td>
							<td align="right">6</td>
							<td align="right">1</td>
							<td align="right">16</td>
							<td align="right">5</td>
							<td align="right">18.8</td>
							<td align="left">Number of right answers x 2</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td colspan="7">
								<hr/>
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td align="left">Sentence completion (A2)</td>
							<td align="right">10</td>
							<td align="right">0.5</td>
							<td align="right">20</td>
							<td align="right">4</td>
							<td align="right">12</td>
							<td align="left">Number of right answers x 2</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td colspan="7">
								<hr/>
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td align="left">Concepts (A3)</td>
							<td align="right">8</td>
							<td align="right">0.5</td>
							<td align="right">24</td>
							<td align="right">3</td>
							<td align="right">7.5</td>
							<td align="left">Partial credit system (1 and 2 points for right
								answers); sum of credit points</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td colspan="7">
								<hr/>
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td align="left">Same - Different (A4)</td>
							<td align="right">20</td>
							<td align="right">0.5</td>
							<td align="right">40</td>
							<td align="right">2</td>
							<td align="right">3</td>
							<td align="left">Number of right answers – number of wrong answers</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td colspan="7">
								<hr/>
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td align="left">Symbol- Digit (A5)</td>
							<td align="right">20</td>
							<td align="right">0.5</td>
							<td align="right">120</td>
							<td align="right">3</td>
							<td align="right">1.5</td>
							<td align="left">Number of right answers x 3/10</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td colspan="7">
								<hr/>
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td align="left">Computation (B1)</td>
							<td align="right">10</td>
							<td align="right">1</td>
							<td align="right">22</td>
							<td align="right">4</td>
							<td align="right">10.9</td>
							<td align="left">Number of right answers x 2</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td colspan="7">
								<hr/>
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td align="left">Information (B2)</td>
							<td align="right">16</td>
							<td align="right">0.5</td>
							<td align="right">40</td>
							<td align="right">4</td>
							<td align="right">6</td>
							<td align="left">Number of right answers</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td colspan="7">
								<hr/>
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td align="left">Vocabulary (B3)</td>
							<td align="right">15</td>
							<td align="right">0.5</td>
							<td align="right">40</td>
							<td align="right">3</td>
							<td align="right">4.5</td>
							<td align="left">Number of right answers – number of wrong answers</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td colspan="7">
								<hr/>
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td align="left">Analogies (B4)</td>
							<td align="right">12</td>
							<td align="right">0.5</td>
							<td align="right">32</td>
							<td align="right">3</td>
							<td align="right">5.6</td>
							<td align="left">Number of right answers</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td colspan="7">
								<hr/>
							</td>
						</tr>
						<tr>
							<td align="left">Comparisons (B5)</td>
							<td align="right">20</td>
							<td align="right">0.5</td>
							<td align="right">50</td>
							<td align="right">2</td>
							<td align="right">2.4</td>
							<td align="left">Number of right answers – number of wrong answers</td>
						</tr>
					</table>
				</table-wrap>

				<p>A and B scales were printed and administered as independent tests. Both booklets
					included the title page for a person’s background information. Information on
					the title page was used to join data from scales A and B into one record. As a
					rule, the A scale was used first and the B after a little break. In several
					cases the testing took place over several days.</p>
			</sec>

			<sec>
				<title>Quality control</title>
				<p>The scoring and data computerization were checked twice. We also used logic
					analysis (possible values of computerized data) and checked for extreme values
					(age). It was possible to check the declared age (years and months) by comparing
					the birth and testing date.</p>
				<p>In both cohorts there were some test booklets that were only superficially
					completed (sporadic answers in one or several subtests); these results were not
					included in the data file. The number of such test booklets was very small
					(&lt;10). We interpreted this as an indicator of a lack of any motivation to do
					well on the test.</p>
			</sec>
			<sec>
				<title>Ethical issues</title>
				<p>The testing of both cohorts was done in accordance with the local guidelines of
					student examination and testing. In 1933/36 the testing was supported by the
					Estonian Ministry of Education. There is no evidence that some schools did not
					allow students to take the test. Evidently one of the main criteria of school
					selection was the location of the school, this was due to the transport cost and
					time resources. The majority of schools were located in the same region
					(southern Estonia) as the researcher's office.</p>
				<p>In 2006 the decision to allow testing was made at the school level. Some school
					authorities refused to take part as the testing disturbs educational process.
					The testing was done during regular school hours in regular classrooms.
					Actually, since testing took place during an ordinary school-day all the
					students were asked to take part. The participation was voluntary for students
					(both in 1934/36 and in 2006) in the sense that the test-takers were not forced
					to take the test, and the test had no consequences for the test-takers. In both
					cohorts there were some students (about 1%) who filled out the tests in a very
					superficial manner (occasional answers). We interpret this as a formal
					conformity to take the test without any real interest in doing well on it.
					Test-booklets with only random answers were not included in the data-file.</p>
				<p>The testing was not anonymous – test-takers had to write their names and
					background data on the first sheet of the test booklet (school, grade, their
					parents’ employment, the number of children in the family and their birth order,
					the parents’ birth place, age, ethnicity). The Estonian adaptation required more
					personal information from students than the original NIT. Presenting personal
					information in testing and school examinations was a relatively typical practice
					in Estonia. In some cases, in the test booklets, the corresponding fields about
					personal information on the test-booklets were left empty, or filled in very
					generally.</p>
				<p>Estonian regulations do not require additional parental approval for testing
					students in schools. All data is sufficiently anonymised to prevent
					identification of individual students (based on the information in the data
					files).</p>
				<p>The completed historical test booklets are in the public archive. Personal
					information from the 2006 cohort is not publicly available and not used in any
					way. The test-takers, their parents and teachers were not given individual
					feedback on the test results. In our research we operated under the ethical
					testing and examination standards accepted by the Estonian educational system.
				</p>
			</sec>
		</sec>
		<sec>
			<title>(3) Dataset description</title>
			<sec>
				<title>Object name</title>
				<p>Data: FE_1933_2006_data.csv</p>
				<p>Description of variables and coding: FE_1933_2006_variables_and_coding.csv</p>
			</sec>
			<sec>
				<title>Data type</title>
				<p>The file consists of secondary data. This means that direct answers are coded
					according to a key at the item level (true, wrong, missing). In one subtest (A5)
					the right, wrong and missing answers were tallied at the test site by the test
					administrators, from the test booklet.</p>
			</sec>
			<sec>
				<title>Format names and versions</title>
				<p>The files format: comma separated variables (.csv).</p>
			</sec>
			<sec>
				<title>Data collectors</title>
				<p>
					<list list-type="bullet">
						<list-item>
							<p>Vilve Raudik (preparation of the new test layout, testing, data
								coding).</p>
						</list-item>
						<list-item>
							<p>Triin Lett (testing, data coding).</p>
						</list-item>
						<list-item>
							<p>Ene Karja (archival work).</p>
						</list-item>
						<list-item>
							<p>Aasa Must (data collection, archival research with historical data,
								data coding).</p>
						</list-item>
						<list-item>
							<p>Olev Must (data collection, archival research with historical data,
								data coding).</p>
						</list-item>
					</list>
				</p>
			</sec>
			<sec>
				<title>Language</title>
				<p>The test language was Estonian. Data documentation is in English.</p>
			</sec>
			<sec>
				<title>License</title>
				<p>CCO</p>
			</sec>
			<sec>
				<title>Embargo</title>
				<p>None.</p>
			</sec>
			<sec>
				<title>Repository location</title>
				<p><uri>http://doi.org/10.7910/DVN/23791</uri></p>
			</sec>
			<sec>
				<title>Publication date</title>
				<p>01 January 2014</p>
			</sec>
		</sec>

		<sec>
			<title>(4) Reuse potential</title>
			<p>The data set is quite extensive because it includes item-level data from nine of the
				10 NIT subtests of two large cohorts. The data may be reused for different purposes:
				e.g. (1) re-analysis of the results in the <italic>Intelligence</italic> paper, (2)
				for teaching purposes, and (3) for further analysis (including collaborative
				projects with Must and Must). The data is useful for advanced psychometric analyses
				at both the item level (Item Response Theory models) and/or the scale level
				(Structural Equation Modelling with latent variables) for the study of the Flynn
				Effect, or sex differences.</p>
		</sec>
	</body>
	<back>
		<ack>
			<title>Acknowledgements</title>
			<p>
				<list>
					<list-item>
						<p>Vello Paatsi (Estonian Literary Museum, Estonia)</p>
					</list-item>
					<list-item>
						<p>Jelte Wicherts (Tilburg University, The Netherlands)</p>
					</list-item>
					<list-item>
						<p>A. Alexander Beaujean (Baylor University, United States)</p>
					</list-item>
				</list>
			</p>
		</ack>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
			<ref id="B1">
				<element-citation publication-type="journal">
					<person-group person-group-type="author">
						<name>
							<surname>Must</surname>
							<given-names>O</given-names>
						</name>
						<name>
							<surname>Must</surname>
							<given-names>A</given-names>
						</name>
					</person-group>
					<article-title>Changes in test-taking patterns over time</article-title>
					<source>Intelligence</source>
					<year iso-8601-date="2013">2013</year>
					<volume>41</volume>
					<fpage>780</fpage>
					<lpage>790</lpage>
					<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.intell.2013.04.005</pub-id>
				</element-citation>
			</ref>
			<ref id="B2">
				<element-citation publication-type="book">
					<person-group person-group-type="author">
						<name>
							<surname>Brigham</surname>
							<given-names>C</given-names>
						</name>
					</person-group>
					<source>A Study of American Intelligence</source>
					<year iso-8601-date="1923">1923</year>
					<publisher-loc>Princeton</publisher-loc>
					<publisher-name>Princeton University Press</publisher-name>
				</element-citation>
			</ref>
			<ref id="B3">
				<element-citation publication-type="book">
					<person-group person-group-type="author">
						<name>
							<surname>Haggerty</surname>
							<given-names>M</given-names>
						</name>
						<name>
							<surname>Terman</surname>
							<given-names>L</given-names>
						</name>
						<name>
							<surname>Thorndike</surname>
							<given-names>E</given-names>
						</name>
						<name>
							<surname>Whipple</surname>
							<given-names>G</given-names>
						</name>
						<name>
							<surname>Yerkes</surname>
							<given-names>R</given-names>
						</name>
					</person-group>
					<source>National Intelligence Tests. Manual of Directions. For Use with
						Scale A, Form 1 and Scale B, Form 1</source>
					<year iso-8601-date="1920">1920</year>
					<publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>
					<publisher-name>World Book Company</publisher-name>
				</element-citation>
			</ref>
			<ref id="B4">
				<element-citation publication-type="book">
					<person-group person-group-type="author">
						<name>
							<surname>Terman</surname>
							<given-names>L</given-names>
						</name>
					</person-group>
					<source>The Intelligence of School Children</source>
					<year iso-8601-date="1921">1921</year>
					<publisher-loc>London</publisher-loc>
					<publisher-name>George G. Harrap</publisher-name>
				</element-citation>
			</ref>
			<ref id="B5">
				<element-citation publication-type="journal">
					<person-group person-group-type="author">
						<name>
							<surname>Whipple</surname>
							<given-names>G</given-names>
						</name>
					</person-group>
					<article-title>The National Intelligence Tests</article-title>
					<source>The Journal of 	Educational Research</source>
					<year iso-8601-date="1921">1921</year>
					<volume>4</volume>
					<fpage>16</fpage>
					<lpage>31</lpage>
				</element-citation>
			</ref>
			<ref id="B6">
				<element-citation publication-type="book">
					<person-group person-group-type="author">
						<name>
							<surname>Tork</surname>
							<given-names>J</given-names>
						</name>
					</person-group>
					<source>Eesti laste intelligents</source>
					<year iso-8601-date="1940">1940</year>
					<publisher-loc>Tartu</publisher-loc>
					<publisher-name>Koolivara</publisher-name>
				</element-citation>
			</ref>
			<ref id="B7">
				<element-citation publication-type="book">
					<person-group person-group-type="author">
						<name>
							<surname>Yoakum</surname>
							<given-names>C</given-names>
						</name>
						<name>
							<surname>Yerkes</surname>
							<given-names>R</given-names>
						</name>
					</person-group>
					<source>Army Mental Tests</source>
					<year iso-8601-date="1920">1920</year>
					<publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>
					<publisher-name>Henry Holt
						and Company</publisher-name>
				</element-citation>
			</ref>
		</ref-list>
		<sec>
			<title>Peer review comments</title>
			<p><uri>http://openpsychologydata.metajnl.com/downloads/peerreview/jopd-ab.pdf</uri></p>
		</sec>
	</back>
</article>
